<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>doubleoseven.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="doubleoseven.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:57:19 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:57:19 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to ze blog</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/welcome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/welcome</guid>
        
        <category>Introduction</category>
        
        <category>Random</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I’ve always found computers fascinating ... </title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;In my family, I’m the girl who’s broken more laptops then anyone else, not because I can’t take care of them, but because I’m always experimenting with them in some way or another. My first laptop used to crashing constantly due to a problem in it’s hard disk (which I believe was kind of my fault) and I remember formatting it each time it refused to turn on, which was quite often. Eventually getting tired of losing data, I learned how to partition my hard disk (because I really didn’t have access to an external hard disk). I was only fourteen at the time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica; min-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;By the time I was in high school, I had a pretty good idea on how to install an operating system from scratch. Everyone in the house considered me the “technician”, requesting me to overlook their computer whenever things got too slow. I also had a knack for solving computer problems by scrolling through forums whenever I was faced with the “blue screen of death” and trying out different solutions. My motto was, and still is: there’s always an answer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica; min-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;Even then, being more interested in playing video games, I never really delved deep enough into the inner workings of the computer, and thus, I never tried my hands at programming (something I deeply regret). This was partly because we never took programming in high school, and I never thought of looking into it myself. That is, until I decided I wanted to major in Computer Science. My decision was greatly influenced by my love for video games. “I want to become a video game developer and influence people with my ideas” -&amp;nbsp; Said my naive younger self. After researching about the field, I decided computer science would be the best way to go. Little did I know about the journey I was about to embark on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica; min-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;“The more I learn about the internet, the more magical it seems.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica; min-height: 13px; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;Most of the courses I’m taking this semester are in someway connected to the Internet: Computer Networks, Web Design and Information Security. And honestly, I have to say, I’m pretty much captivated by what the internet is. Just imagining tiny packets consisting only of 0s and 1s travelling over hundreds of miles only to reach their destination in the form of text, pictures, or video is enough to make my mind whirl. And actually knowing what’s going on behind the scenes, makes waiting for an excruciatingly slow page to load so much more interesting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica;&quot;&gt;#RandomThoughts&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica; font-size: 11px; min-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;-webkit-text-stroke-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); -webkit-text-stroke-width: initial; font-family: Helvetica; font-size: 11px; min-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 21:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/ive-always-found-computers-fascinating</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/ive-always-found-computers-fascinating</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        <category>decisions</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>the internet</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The States 2014 - part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;I love how I end up writing posts titled, &quot;Blalalala - part 1&quot; and yet never get around to writing part 2, or 3 for that matter. I might as well leave out the part 1 to begin with! :p&amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;With that in mind, I thought perhaps I should make a part two post before people start thinking I can&#39;t keep my promises. So here&#39;s part two of our stay in the States.&amp;nbsp;(albeit, a very short post)&amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;(You can find part one &lt;a href=&quot;http://themuslimahtigress.blogspot.com/2014/07/the-states-2014-part-1.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt;&quot;&gt;During the last few days in Louisville, my dad&#39;s friend took us to what they call the walking bridge (officially referred to as the &quot;The Big Four Bridge&quot;). The walking bridge is a pedestrian and bicycle only bridge that was initially made as a railway. Interestingly, it has a line of deaths connected to it’s making and is the only bridge in Louisville to have suffered so many casualties. The bridge connects the two states, Indiana and Kentucky, while passing over the Ohio River.&amp;nbsp;Below are a couple of photographs of our walk (or rather run) across the bridge with frequent stops to take pictures. I was fasting and tired but the exercise was quite refreshing and welcoming. I did suffer some burning in my legs afterwards, but being a bit of a masochist, I really didn&#39;t mind.&amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ET40P2QtbdI/VASsb45BUZI/AAAAAAAAALM/BHYGmH25tKQ/s1600/2014-07-17%2B17.06.06.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ET40P2QtbdI/VASsb45BUZI/AAAAAAAAALM/BHYGmH25tKQ/s1600/2014-07-17%2B17.06.06.jpg&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-GU0xBYUucAQ/VASscJu5UiI/AAAAAAAAALQ/xppx0Clv0vc/s1600/2014-07-17%2B17.06.19.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-GU0xBYUucAQ/VASscJu5UiI/AAAAAAAAALQ/xppx0Clv0vc/s1600/2014-07-17%2B17.06.19.jpg&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BlOEkJLK8xE/VASschrykfI/AAAAAAAAALg/58FcC5rwZn4/s1600/2014-07-17%2B17.22.59.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BlOEkJLK8xE/VASschrykfI/AAAAAAAAALg/58FcC5rwZn4/s1600/2014-07-17%2B17.22.59.jpg&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-f9bF_Ptenqg/VASsc4rlzGI/AAAAAAAAALY/yqwAqJ0UZz4/s1600/2014-07-17%2B21.37.41.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-f9bF_Ptenqg/VASsc4rlzGI/AAAAAAAAALY/yqwAqJ0UZz4/s1600/2014-07-17%2B21.37.41.jpg&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 20:54:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/the-states-2014-part-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/the-states-2014-part-2</guid>
        
        <category>The big four bridge</category>
        
        <category>the states</category>
        
        <category>summer 2014</category>
        
        <category>Louisville</category>
        
        <category>traveling</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Musings of a Senior Student</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;University has started again. I’m not sure if I should be excited or not – this being my last year and all. I guess I should be because once university is over, I can go back to doing what I love best: sleeping. Ah, how much I love that deep slumber where your mind is oblivious of all the worries in the world. It really is the best feeling ever. That is, until your mind is plagued with dark desolate dreams that seem insistent on staying. My “nightmares”, unlike some, do not consist of monsters and dragons (those are actually quite cool) but rather entail situations which deep down, I fear.&amp;nbsp; Upon waking, I’m more likely to remember the feelings I felt while having the dream rather than the details –such as the people that were present and my surroundings. That means it’s very difficult for me to describe the dream later on – as describing feelings, especially for me, is not an easy task. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;On the other hand, graduation means I’ve got other things to worry about. Such as:&amp;nbsp;whether to continue with my Masters right after or to work. Although I love learning and in the past would not have hesitated with such a decision, I’ve come to realize that attending lectures and reading textbooks really isn’t for me.&amp;nbsp; Being a goody two shoes all my life, I’ve never actually skipped a single class (alright, maybe I’m exaggerating just a bit). But during this past summer, I&#39;ve come to realize I learn best when I’m experimenting, thinking, and applying – all of which, I believe, passive environments fail to provide. I learn more by “doing”, and fail to see the point of theoretical concepts unless they’re presented in a practical fashion. Even with alternative methods of learning such as projects that allow you to learn through experimentation, some universities insist on using the traditional approach of lecture based learning (or maybe that’s just my university). That is why I’m having doubts of continuing my studies when I could be out in the field, putting to practice all the theoretical knowledge that is currently in my head. &amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 20:18:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/musings-of-senior-student</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/musings-of-senior-student</guid>
        
        <category>nightmares</category>
        
        <category>senior student</category>
        
        <category>hands on learning vs traditional teaching</category>
        
        <category>university</category>
        
        <category>dreams</category>
        
        <category>musings</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The States 2014 - part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;It’s like there’s a huge block in my head that’s preventing me from writing. I feel stupid. I need to go out and get some physical exercise. All this cleaning and shopping seriously isn’t for me. I mean come on. Just the other day I ended up buying myself a pair of pink shoes. Me. Buying pink shoes. I don’t even like shoes. Or at least I pretend I don’t. *sigh*&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;***&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;This is my attempt to blog while I’m here in the States. Initially, I wanted to record everything that happened on this trip and post it on my blog. Kind of like a written vlog. But that hasn&#39;t seemed to work out *see previous post* I’m going to blame the lack of exercise and overeating.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;***&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;I know it’s Ramadan and I should be directing my energy to reading Quran and praying but for some reasons I don’t feel like doing anything. All I want to do is sleep and sleep and sleep.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;***&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;So far, I&#39;ve written two tiny posts. It seems I’m doing quite well as long as I keep my posts short. Extremely short. Did I mention I feel stupid? &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;***&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;So I guess I should mention some of the places we’ve been to in the past week here in Louisville. You’ve probably guessed by now that we’ve done a lot of shopping – and you’ll be surprised to know a lot of food shopping. There are actually a lot of Halal food stores here. Pretty convenient, huh? The first time we walked into a grocery store, which happened to be Kroger’s; we ended up spending around a hundred dollars. On food. &amp;nbsp;That’s what happens when you send a bunch of fasting kids into a grocery store and everything looks so good. We did end up having to check everything we picked up for the letters UD or kosher (which is as halal as stuff gets over here). This lead to loud whispers across the aisles asking if the chocolate chip cookies cookies we’d picked up were Halal or not. Unfortunately, we couldn’t find kosher bread but upon asking two of the staff members there, they kindly redirected us to a Kroger’s that did sell kosher bread. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;***&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Have I also mentioned that people here are genuinely nice? As we were leaving Kroger’s, a young boy of ten or eleven, stopped while passing by just to say “Asalamualaikum”.&amp;nbsp; Another lady at Macy’s greeted us the same way. People keep asking where we’re from and every time I mention Saudi, they usually mention a relative or friend they know living there. A guy at Target came up to us while we were looking at bed sheets and after finding out we’re from Saudi, stated that he was learning Arabic and greeted us with “Kaifahaluk?”. We ended up having a mini Arabic lesson right then and there. Personally, I think it’s great that people are so warm towards us. That isn’t to say that people don’t stare and look at us weird when we first walk into any store. But I&#39;d like to think they’re more curious than anything else.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Here’s the view from outside our apartment:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-laCNpS4kNU8/U7w3_svm5QI/AAAAAAAAAKU/W0HblGPcqXM/s1600/10463052_10152535439211101_9104578051691376053_n.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-laCNpS4kNU8/U7w3_svm5QI/AAAAAAAAAKU/W0HblGPcqXM/s1600/10463052_10152535439211101_9104578051691376053_n.jpg&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Random Louisville pictures:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-MGxYhCf4WHI/U7w4AlcCqzI/AAAAAAAAAKc/9tYxnj4TNo4/s1600/10511340_10152527956936101_7422537780337543532_n.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-MGxYhCf4WHI/U7w4AlcCqzI/AAAAAAAAAKc/9tYxnj4TNo4/s1600/10511340_10152527956936101_7422537780337543532_n.jpg&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5nHn4o0Kx4Q/U7w4CwkWHCI/AAAAAAAAAKk/3flyBUTnPCo/s1600/10514475_10152527957276101_120263596262334375_n.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5nHn4o0Kx4Q/U7w4CwkWHCI/AAAAAAAAAKk/3flyBUTnPCo/s1600/10514475_10152527957276101_120263596262334375_n.jpg&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Congrats, I actually managed to write 500+&amp;nbsp;words. *Gives self a cookie*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Oops, I&#39;m fasting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 21:38:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/the-states-2014-part-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/the-states-2014-part-1</guid>
        
        <category>Vacation</category>
        
        <category>Log</category>
        
        <category>Summer</category>
        
        <category>Blogging</category>
        
        <category>USA</category>
        
        <category>Random Thoughts</category>
        
        <category>Louisville</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Redemption: Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;A short story I&#39;ve been writing for a while, just for fun. Haven&#39;t finished it yet but I thought if I posted it on my blog, I might be motivated to do so. Hope you enjoy it and comments are more than welcome. :)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lightning crashed - hitting the earth above him and he trembled from the very thought of accidentally letting go. The world around him was a mixture of electric blue and gray swirling collectively in the pouring heavy rain as he hung off the edge of the cliff desperately clinging for his life. His clothes were drenched; rainwater running in rivulets from his dark hair and through the creases in his shirt. He grit his teeth as he pushed his hands against the moist soil - using all his strength in his attempt to pull himself up. Beads of sweat mixed with water trickled down his forehead; his breath came out in short spasms and fear shone clearly though his bluish-green eyes. Above him the sound of the rain as it pounded the earth could be heard echoing through the darkness wrapped around him. He was terrified; and yet all the strength in the world could not assist in saving him from what was his doom. His fragile heart beat hard against his chest and he felt as if he were drowning in this sheet of rain that seemed to envelop him in a deathly embrace. There was a clap of thunder and a lightning bolt lit up the yawning night sky and suddenly he felt a searing pain escalate throughout his entire body. He gasped in response unable to withstand the pain that made him feel as if his very veins were on fire. His unoccupied hand reached up to rub his temples as a quiet moan escaped his lips &quot;Why? Why me? What have &lt;i&gt;I d&lt;/i&gt;one to deserve this?&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The sound of the rain subsided and it was then that a deep low voice responded to him from within the darkness shaking the very platform on which he clutched onto with his dear life. &quot;Shall I show you?&quot; The man, taken by surprise frantically turned his head towards the direction of the voice trying to pinpoint its location. &quot;Who are you?&quot;He shouted uneasily into the void. &quot;I am the guardian of this wretched place&quot; &quot;Guardian?&quot; &quot;Yes. Long ago the souls of the dead would be brought here to be punished by the command of Master Hades. Over the years, the humans stopped worshiping the great Kings - Zeus, Poseidon and Hades and with each passing year the power of the Olympians diminished. With Hades no longer the King of the Underworld - the souls had no obligation to recompense for the crimes they had committed during their lives - they merely passed on - turning into dust and vanishing&quot; Confused, the man shook his head &quot;If the souls become dust upon death - why am I still here?&quot; &quot;Your questions shall be answered in time. For now, let me show you&quot; The voice trailed off like a shadow trailing in the dust. &quot;Show me what?&quot; The man&#39;s voice was hoarse - his breathing ragged and hot against his hand. The voice didn&#39;t respond.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Time passed. Seconds? Minutes? Hours? By now the man felt an inner desire to let go - to let go and plummet into the hands of whatever fate had stored for him. His entire body throbbed - his arms ached and his heart had not ceased to pound fiercely against his chest. It was then that from within the grayish-blue chaos a lightning bolt crashed into the edge of cliff - exceedingly close to where the man clung onto with his slowly diminishing strength. Electric blue sparks sprung from the impact and landed on his hand causing him to howl out in pain and agony. His hand slipped - the pain being too much to bear and before he knew it he was falling into the bottomless void that lay below him.&amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;To be continued ...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:18:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/redemption-part-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/redemption-part-1</guid>
        
        <category>Percy Jackson and the Olympians</category>
        
        <category>Short Stories</category>
        
        <category>Creative Writing</category>
        
        <category>Redemption</category>
        
        <category>Greek Mythology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coherence in the Quran:</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; The Quran has 114 Surahs (I will translate that to &#39;chapters&#39; at the moment) – all of which were revealed at different times and these Surahs are divided into two categories:&lt;div&gt;&lt;ol style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 7pt; text-indent: -0.25in;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot; style=&quot;text-indent: -0.25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-indent: -0.25in;&quot;&gt;Makki Surahs (Surahs revealed in Makkah - the main audience were the Quraish – most Ayat are an introduction to Allah, His signs, Paradise, Hell Fire and the Day of Judgment)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-indent: -0.25in;&quot;&gt;Madani Surahs (Surahs revealed in Madinah, the main audience were the Muslims)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoListParagraphCxSpLast&quot; style=&quot;mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; The Quran starts with Surah Al Fatihah and ends with Surah Al Naas – at first glance, one may wonder what kind of order the Surahs in the Quran are in? The word Surah, although normally translated in English to “chapter” does not properly explain the word Surah. The word Surah was used in the olden days to refer to the outer walls of a city inside which you had many things going on all of which were connected. So with that in mind, let’s discuss some of the possibilities.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; Clearly the Quran is not in chronological order: for if it was, the first Surah would be Surah&amp;nbsp;Al-Alaq (which in fact is placed near the end).&amp;nbsp;It is not in size order either (Biggest Surah first and smallest last) because then the last Surah would have been Surah Al Kauthar which is not the case. And neither is it in subject order with for example, Taqwa (piety) discussed first, Eman (faith) second etc. nor does it deal with a single subject matter one at a time. The conclusion many may eventually arrive to is that seeing as each Surah is independent of each other, there must not be a connection. Many scholars believe that this is not the case (for concrete reasons that are too long to go into at the moment): just as the order of each Ayah is set by Allah, the order of each Surah in the Quran is also according to Him. With this knowledge they studied the order of the Surahs in-depth and found many beautiful connections between the Surahs and here I will share with you just one such finding. In Surah Ar- Rahman and Surah Al Waqiah, (the 55&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;and 56&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Surahs in the Quran), one of the connections between them can be seen when listing the subjects discussed in each Surah.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;55- Surah Ar-Rahman -&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Subjects discussed in order:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;1) Greatness of the Quran (Ayat (signs) in the Book)&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;2) List of Allah&#39;s favors (Ayat (signs) around you.)&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;3) What happens to people who fail to be grateful? Day of Judgment and Hellfire. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;4) People of paradise and what they get. (Tour of paradise)&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;5) Tour of Elite paradise. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;56- Surah Al Waqiah -&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Subjects discussed in order:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;1) The Elite. (Who will be rewarded elite paradise)&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;2) People of the right hand (Who will be rewarded paradise)&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;3) Hell fire and Day of Judgment.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;4) The favors of Allah. (Ayat (signs) around you)&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;5) Greatness of the Quran (Ayat (signs) in the Book)&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;As you can see, the subjects are reflected in the Surah right after it – this is just one example of the divine connections between each Surah in the Quran. (There can even be multiple connections as well)&amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taken from Ustadh Nouman Ali Khan’s Divine Speech Seminar videos which can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bayyinah.tv/&quot;&gt;Bayyinah.tv&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Note: My knowledge of the Quran is extremely limited – this is just my attempt to share with you whatever minute knowledge I know so that maybe you can learn to fall in love with the Quran’s beauty as I have. Any good that came out of this was from Allah and any mistakes are from myself. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 17:37:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/coherence-in-quran</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/coherence-in-quran</guid>
        
        <category>Nouman Ali Khan</category>
        
        <category>Islam</category>
        
        <category>Quran</category>
        
        <category>Bayyinah</category>
        
        <category>Coherence in the Quran</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Doughnuts, Starbucks and Randomness. xD </title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; My baby sister sat at the table with a piece of my brother’s chocolate croissant in front of her.&amp;nbsp; Her voice echoed throughout Starbucks as she proclaimed in a feigned British accent: “Even if we do buy doughnuts afterwards, I wouldn&#39;t be able to eat them”.&amp;nbsp; I shifted my gaze towards the scrumptious piece that lay in the plate in front of her: my hand lazily pointed towards it. “So … I can have that?” Startled, she cried out with a loud “No!” and instantly let out a stream of laughter. I rolled my eyes at her teasingly and continued to sip at the chocolate-chip ice blended drink that rested between my chilled fingers. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; Around us the place was nearly deserted except for a single table a few feet away where my other younger sister sat with her three friends. Despite the place being nearly abandoned, our table alone was probably enough to give the opposite impression. My older sister sat across from me sipping her coffee and making sarcastic remarks, while my brother attempted to imitate King Candy from Reck-it-Ralph at every opportune moment making us all crack up at. And yet, my baby sister was the one who stole the spotlight - from commenting on the ingredients that went into the cake she’d just devoured to friendly bickering with the three of us on how we should act more like ladies (excluding my brother of course) and yet acting like a complete barbarian herself. (Her words, not mine). &lt;i&gt;I &lt;/i&gt;sat with a bemused look on my face – allowing myself to have a chuckle or two at how bloody hilarious we were and shifting from adopting a scowl to doubling over in laughter over something someone had said. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; This picture of today’s outing I have just painted is an unusual one especially with parents like ours (the overly protective kind) who have a habit of calling us up every five minutes to insure we’re still alive and haven’t tripped over our feet and fallen into a ditch – but it’s not as rare as you may think. (Or as rare as I may make it out to be) Although, what initially was supposed to be a visit to Krispy Kreme’s with a group of my younger sister’s friends, it turned out that fate had other plans. Prayer time being right around the corner, the employees at Krispy Kreme’s “kicked” us out the moment we walked in at 3:30 on the basis of it nearly being Salah (prayer) time and so they simply could not have customers. This resulted in the eight of us walking across the street (our drivers having all gone home) towards Starbucks and Krispy Kreme’s losing a couple of potential customers. (Well, not really. We did go back to buy from them anyway) &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; We ended up staying in Starbucks till almost five in the evening after which we walked back to Krispy Kreme’s and bought a box full of doughnuts for my parents. Later at home, we related the events to our mother who by now should be used to our random escapades – but was surprised nonetheless. I’m just glad we got back in one piece. (Mentally, that is) xP &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 20:09:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/doughnuts-starbucks-and-randomness-xd</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/doughnuts-starbucks-and-randomness-xd</guid>
        
        <category>Jeddah</category>
        
        <category>Doughnuts</category>
        
        <category>Sisters. Randomness</category>
        
        <category>Starbucks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A few things I&#39;ve noticed about myself:</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;I love making lists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I know I&#39;ve mentioned this before but: I am literally obsessed with cute things. No seriously – I think it’s escalated into a mental disorder. O_o If you know a good psychiatrist*, please do refer them to me.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I prefer the easy way out of things – in others words, I’m lazy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I have a knack for wasting time by staring at my laptop screen. Probably the &lt;i&gt;only &amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;talent I possess.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I can be laughing one minute and completely moody the next – I blame the hormones.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I try too hard to be funny.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I really do like writing lists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I’m only writing this because I have nothing else better to do with my life&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No, idiot – you should be watching a programming tutorial right now.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I like talking to myself.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I also like programming … And math. You’re welcome to call me a nerd – in any case, that title was claimed by me long time ago.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I will now end this and go back to sulking in a corner.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: .25in;&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 02:35:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/a-few-things-ive-noticed-about-myself</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/a-few-things-ive-noticed-about-myself</guid>
        
        <category>Lists</category>
        
        <category>Randomness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Remember: Little snippets of my life in Saudi:</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Seeing as I once did an “&lt;a href=&quot;http://themuslimahtigress.blogspot.com/2013/03/memories-i-remember.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;I remember&lt;/a&gt;” post centering around our time in America, I thought I’d do one for our time here in Jeddah. I&#39;ve lived here for the past thirteen years and to be perfectly honest with you, I&#39;ve got some great memories of the place. Regardless of what you may have heard or read, Jeddah like any other place has its ups and downs and considering the fact that I was born here and half of my mother’s family lives here I&#39;ve grown to love the place as my own. (No, I’m not Saudi, in case you’re wondering). &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;So here goes my list of memories: I hope you enjoy them!&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember playing with the two stay kittens that lived in the bushes outside my grandparent’s house. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember letting them climb all over my legs - they’re tiny claws scratching my skin. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember the countless sleepovers at my grandparent’s house – (their new and former one) – the late night talks with my cousin, the stories she would demand I tell her (I did enjoy telling them, I promise!), and the secrets we would exchange in the dead of the night.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember watching my uncle (who was just a teen back then) play Metal Gear and countless other video games such as Need For Speed, Fear, GTA, and one featuring a Japanese character – he never did tell us what that one was called despite all the begging we did. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember the cold air that always escaped through the space beneath the door of my uncle’s room – I remember taking turns with my sister, putting our feet as close as we could, savoring the freezing cold air. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember the countless fights I had with my cousin: most revolving around me wanting to sit down with a book and her wanting me to play tag, or hide-and-seek or whatever it was we used to play in those days. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember the bird we nursed back to health that had been injured in a fall, and later watching it fly away in to the sky – strong and healthy again. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember playing games that consisted of filling our room up with foam balls – pushing the mattress off the bed to make ourselves a ship – and setting the air conditioner to absurd temperatures so we could pretend we’d reached Antarctica. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember my days in primary and middle school – how I was always considered the “quiet”, “shy” kid and how much I inwardly &lt;i&gt;hated&lt;/i&gt;that. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember lying to my sixth grade teacher about showing my report card to my mother because I was too afraid to tell her the truth – she saw right through me on the spot.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember being such a clean freak, where every speck of dust would annoy the hell out of me.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember dropping a huge bowl golabjamen&lt;sup&gt;(1)&lt;/sup&gt;right in front of some late night guests - the syrup ended up running down my pants and onto the floor while I just stood there dumbstruck.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember my mother becoming furious, and my father gently telling me it was alright. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember the long bus rides back from school, hanging out with the older girls in the back – and falling asleep by the time we reached our stop.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember the messed up jokes my friends would make in high school – the headaches we gave our teachers - especially the social worker, and the good times we all shared.&amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember hanging out in the deputy headmistress’s office while collaborating on the school magazine my friend Miriam and I were in charge of. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember dressing up as a guy once while our grandmother (Allah Yarhamha&lt;sup&gt;(2)&lt;/sup&gt;) was staying with us – her reaction was to pretend I was some stranger from the streets and to keep telling me to get out – I just stood there, doubling up in laughter. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember when our aunt and her sons would visit from the states, the family get-togethers we’d have, mostly consisting of all of us cousins crowding around our uncles and annoying the hell out of them. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember riding my uncle’s quad bike over the sand dunes in the outskirts of Jeddah. &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember attempting a dive into the Red Sea on one of our recent trips there, and ending up with a nose full of water instead.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember performing my first Hajj when I was sixteen –&amp;nbsp; camping out in Mina while rain fell from the skies,&amp;nbsp; asking for forgiveness in Arafat and sleeping under the night sky in Muzdalifah.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember getting my first (unofficial) marriage proposal on Hajj from some random Egyptian lady who thought I’d be good for her son – now THAT was awkward.&amp;nbsp; &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember riding my younger cousin’s bike (which I &quot;borrowed&quot; on the spot from him) down the street next to the highway because I was too tired to run and catch up with my sister and uncle who were way&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%;&quot;&gt;ahead.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I remember the late nights where all of us siblings would make corny jokes, tease each other to no end and laugh till our sides hurt and our throats were all raw.&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;sup style=&quot;font-family: Calibri, sans-serif; line-height: 115%;&quot;&gt;(3)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I remember, I remember, I remember&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;My. Thirteen years is a long time. I could probably go on and on, but I think I’ll stop here,&lt;strike&gt; because I think you get the point: Jeddah is awesome - and if you haven&#39;t been here, well, let me just say - you are missing out mate. :p (Okay - that was totally not needed. Sigh. I suck at humor)&lt;/strike&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;*Scratches that all out* The real point is: no matter where you are, be thankful for the people and moments in your life (even if things don&#39;t always go the way you want them to) - because you never know when all that will be taken away. Sometimes, we need to look past all the &quot;bad&quot; times to realize how blessed we actually are - and I&#39;d say &lt;i&gt;I&#39;m&lt;/i&gt; extremely blessed. Alhamdulilah (Praise to God).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;(1) An Indian/Pakistani&amp;nbsp;dessert&amp;nbsp;which you MUST try.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;(2) An Arabic phrase which means: May God have mercy on her soul.&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(3) We still do that. =)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 01:53:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>doubleoseven.github.io/i-remember-little-snippets-of-my-life</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">doubleoseven.github.io/i-remember-little-snippets-of-my-life</guid>
        
        <category>Jeddah</category>
        
        <category>Saudi Arabia</category>
        
        <category>Memories</category>
        
        <category>I Remember</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
